hey what's up guys my name is a Cherno
and welcome to 2018 and welcome back to
my safe hotspot series and today we're
going to be talking all about the auto
keyword so in C++ so far we've been
using types for all of our variables and
basically all of our data so we've got
types like integers doubles you know
strings classes structs all this kind of
stuff pointers instead of using all of
that is actually a way to let C++
automatically deduce what the type is of
data that we're either creating so by
initializing a variable or simply kind
of assigning from one variable to
another so what I mean by that is
suppose that we have a string with
creditors string and then maybe we have
a function our class that returns a
string we know that the type that it's
returning is string and of course so
does the compiler so when we actually
assign that return type but that return
value to act like a local variable in
our current function instead of us
having to actually type string you know
name a variable equals get name or
something we can just type order and
then our variable name and it will
automatically work out what the type is
supposed to be now this lends itself to
a few good things and a few bad things
and we're going to kind of discuss that
today this is gonna be more of an open
discussion because the actual can't like
the actual concept of order is really
really simple and it's not there's not
gonna be much point I think in me just
taking like 10 minutes talking about
what Auto actually is because once I
show you you'll be like ah okay
there's not much to it really and I mean
we can use order in like in like a few
kind of complicated ways but for the
most part it is very simple so what this
kind of ends up becoming it's one of
those episodes where it's like well you
can use it like this but you probably
shouldn't go to kind of overboard with
it and we'll definitely be discussing
that kind of stuff so anyway let's just
jump into some code and take a look at
some examples of how order actually
works where you can use it and all that
stuff so if I make a variable here and
I'll just write into a equals five
that's my variable done pretty simple
stuff what I can now do is instead of
like I don't know creating another low
like let's just say this is very simple
example and probably meaningless but
let's just say that I want to create
another variable called B which has the
value of a right well instead of typing
int I can just type Auto and what this
will actually do if I hover my mouse
that would be in Visual Studio you'll
see it actually says into B because it's
automatically worked out okay well
you're assigning B to B a so what I'm
going to do is automatically work out
that well a is an integer or therefore B
is also an integer and I can kind of
print that normally as as if it was well
anything really because it's just a
normal variable and that will all work
fine
I can also kind of replace this int here
with Auto as well and if I hover my
mouse over this you'll see it says ena
and the way that it kind of works that
out is it sees well five if you just
write a numeric kind of literal like
this it is automatically gonna be an
integer if I kind of type in an owl or
something here then you can see that it
actually makes it a long and if I was to
do five point five F of course it's
going to become a float and if I wrote
not an O a string like churner like this
you can see it becomes a Const our
pointer so basically you can see that I
can I can I kind of have two things that
going on here first of all I don't need
to care so much about the type this is
where C++ can kind of kind of turn into
a weakly typed language where instead of
being a strongly typed language where we
always specify this as an end this is a
flow to this is a string this is
whatever class is whatever type we can
just kind of write Watto everywhere and
we don't have to deal with types at all
like ever there's one thing it can
become but also it means that we can
kind of in our code this actual thing if
we want this to change we don't
necessarily have to change the type ever
like this left side of this kind of
equation here left side of the equal
sign this stay is ordere all the time no
matter what this is no matter if it like
it's like some kind of non point or an
actual value or a string or whatever it
could possibly be or just a single
character we don't have to change any of
this so this lends itself to two things
and we're going to kind of discuss this
for the rest of the episode probably and
that is well if I have author then do I
really need to ever write any type
can't I just use order everywhere and
that's it that's like it's a valid
question I'm not gonna pretend it's not
but it's also it also comes down to a
matter of style and also you need to
think about what the benefits and what
the setbacks are for kind of that style
of programming and we'll definitely get
into that but anyway let's let's
actually dive into some examples where
order might be useful and why like how I
use auto and all that so going back to
our kind of simple example here we've
established that order can basically be
used to automatically deduce what the
type of a variable is now in this case
we're just assigning it immediately here
it's clear to us what this type is so I
would probably just write the type
because that makes the code a lot
cleaner now suppose that I had a
function that return the string and it's
called get name and it may be return
churner so if I have something like this
and now I then want to actually store
that string as a local variable I would
need to type a city string and then
maybe name equals get name just like
that but what I can do of course is
instead of this I can use order name
equals get name like that and now this
name will automatically be deduced to be
an STD string of course because we're
assigning it to the value of get name
which returns a string and we don't
actually have to write sed string at all
what this also means though is that if I
over here go and change this type to
like char get name or something like
that that gets updated here so I don't
actually need to change my code twice
which can be quite useful because if I
start changing my API then client-side
you can see no code has changed inside
this main function nothing has changed
however I've changed the return type up
here if we were using an STD string here
we would actually need to change the
return type or we would need to change
this somehow because we're returning a
char and we're just assigning it to an
STD string now technically speaking this
in this example it would work because
there is an implicit constructor for
string that actually takes in a child
pointer but the whole thing kind of
changes because like I can call name dot
size or something like that with this
thing but if I was just using order you
know that's not something that would
work for this case
but if I went back to a city string
suddenly yes it would so that's kind of
two sides of the coin right on one hand
it means that if I change my API if I
change the return type forget name to be
an SUV string I decide to maybe change
it to a char pointer in the future then
client-side I don't need to change
anything that's great I don't even know
that the API has changed but that's also
a bad thing because I don't know that
the API has changed and in my break code
that relied on that type being a certain
type so you see there's two kind of this
it's it's nice on one hand because you
don't have to change any code but you
that might break stuff for you and it
might be harder for you to deal with
whereas of course if this was actually
said to be an STD string and I actually
end up changing this it's not gonna
break further down or whatever
immediately this will just well in this
case it will actually work perfectly
because it will actually convert it to
be an SAE string so this example is even
more special because in this case order
would actually break our code whereas SE
string doesn't but then again also you
might want it to be a char pointer so
this becomes like a huge kind of details
kind of thing right what it really
depends on what you're dealing with
anyway I don't wanna get too much into
that so for these cases I would never
use order personally because I like
knowing the type of my variables if I'm
just reading this code and I see stuff
like order name like that I don't know
what that is like an III have to either
hop up my mouse over this to heart and
hope the visual Studios intellisense
actually can tell me what the type is or
I actually have to go to the actual
function and see what the return type is
that's a little bit annoying I want to
just be able to look at this code and
say okay name is a string just like that
right to me that's a lot more readable
and it's also less error-prone because
again if the API changes like at and the
end and specifically the API changes in
a way that breaks our code that break
won't go unnoticed and might even result
in a runtime bug or something in the
future because our type is just
magically changed maybe a little bit
maybe they're somewhat compatible kind
of like a child pointer is in a string
pointer is but what if I'm then later
taking
size of that type because I expect to
serialize it or something like that you
know that might destroy everything so I
would definitely not use it in this case
however it is still useful so let me
show you a case in which it's a good
idea to use order so suppose that I
actually had a type that was kind of
lengthy so that well this this - I'll
show you two examples to explain this
first of all let's just start off with
maybe I have a vector of strings and
this is maybe just like I don't know
strings okay and I'm just going to push
back you know apple orange and that'll
be enough for now and then also include
a vector to get access to that okay cool
so I have two strengths and instead and
for some reason instead of like
iterating over them normally I want to
print all of these things instead of
iterating over them normally I'm
actually going to use an iterator so
what that would look like is for STD
vector STD string : : iterator I'll call
it I T equals string stop begin and then
over here we'd have iterator does not
equal string stop and and then iterator
plus plus right and then maybe I'd do
STD see out get rid of the value of the
iterator like that and if I run this
program of mine then of course I get all
the elements inside my vector printing
just like that now iterators aren't
particularly used much nowadays because
well I mean they are but they kind of
you'd probably use a for each loop or
like a range based for loop for
something like this we will probably
talk about iterators in a later episode
but bear with me for this example so you
can see basically what I'm said what I'm
trying to say is that this is the type
is huge right instead of writing this I
can just write order and suddenly that
kind of makes my code a lot more
readable because I don't have to have
this massive time here's another example
of where we might have a massive type
let's just say that I'm just making this
up on the spots that aren't think too
deeply about this actual example but
let's just say I'll have a device
manager right which has maybe like a map
so we'll say STD unordered map
of STD string to STD vector maybe we
have another class of actual kind of
devices so let's do that for now as the
V vector device pointer so we have like
a map of strings to a vector of devices
and these are our our actual devices and
we'll say over here we'll have Const the
type which I'll just copy because huge
will have that other reference
get devices return em devices okay
my magnet Const as well okay so I'll
call I'll come up here and I'll include
unordered map just like that okay so
there we go we have this device manager
of ours I'll just go ahead and try and
use this so down here I'll write device
manager of DM then DM get devices now I
want to assign this to something so what
I have to do of course is assign it to
this massive type and specifically I
wanted to be a Const reference so I'll
come down here and I'll write the type
and then devices now I don't even know
if you can see that because that's such
a long line of code so I'll kind of
maybe drop this down here so this is
that this is the type right it's
absolutely massive now what I could do
right and what I might do is in a
situation like that it's just alias to
type either by using type def or using
so what I could write is using device
map or something like that equals and
then this actual type like that and what
that would mean is that instead of
running this I could just write Const
device map like that and that's final
you can also alternatively if you prefer
and if you want to support I guess older
code basis you could also write type def
the type and then device the map like
that instead of the using okay so either
way though we end up with an actual type
here that is a lot smaller and probably
makes more sense and you could probably
even move this whoops and you can
probably also remove this using kind of
type thing to actually be inside the
device manager class so that when you
include device manager you also have
access to this device map type and that
might be something I would do however if
we don't want to go down there
then of course we do have to actually
have that entire type here which gets
very annoying so this is another valid
use case for auto in my opinion like it
really really helps with this it makes
it a lot smaller now keep in mind with
Auto we still have to use reference okay
if we were to change this to be like
something like order devices like that
without the ampersand it's actually
going to make a copy so it's gonna it's
gonna do the same thing as if I actually
had STD on our map without the ampersand
like that right so we'll actually copy
this entire map into a local variable we
want we don't want to copy it in this
case so we actually have to write Const
Auto reference so that's another thing
to keep in mind with order just because
you might be returning a reference
doesn't mean it's actually gonna sort it
as a reference if you don't write
reference here it's not going to store
it as a reference and it will copy the
variable okay so those are kind of two
real-world examples in which I would
probably use order basically if your
type is just really really long right if
you if your type is like int or string
or something like that then I would
never I don't think I would I would
never use Auto because it just makes the
code less readable it really doesn't
serve any benefit in my opinion but for
long types like this it could be
extremely useful now of course getting
into more complicated code bases and
stuff involving templates and whatnot
there are cases in which you literally
have to use order and there's no way
because you just don't know what the
types are gonna be and that just becomes
massively complicated I personally
prefer to just not get myself into code
bases that are that complicated where
you must use order it because it because
you just don't know what's going on and
there's no way to know what's going on
because that just becomes really really
messy and hard to deal with and hard to
maintain and hard to explain to other
people how that code actually works
because you yourself don't fully
understand how it works of course cuz
it's crazy it's magic but anyway all of
that aside the auto keyword it's also
used for things like trailing return
types or just you can also use them for
functions deciding from staples loss for
teen something like get name you can
actually get that to return an order or
even before that in sequel plus 11 you
can use traffic trailing return types
just like that to actually determine the
type there's a bunch of things that you
can actually do with
that is we're not gonna talk about in
this video because this video is
specifically about order as an actual
type that we use for variables but
that's pretty much it leave your
thoughts as to what you think about Auto
and where and like where or why you use
it in your codebase leave a comment
below I'd love to get like a discussion
started I've told you my opinions
they're just opinions feel free to
disagree with me and tell me why you
disagree with me in the comments below
I'd love to hear your thoughts but to
summarize I basically only use order if
the type is huge and I for some reason
don't want to using or type def like to
create an alias for that type to make it
shorter but apart from that I really
just try and avoid order because it
makes most courage most code just harder
to read and it takes longer to actually
read and understand that code again
something like iterators where you have
a long type I think that's totally valid
alright anyway I hope you guys enjoyed
this video if you did you can hit that
like button you can also help support
the series by going over to patreon icon
for such the channel huge thank you as
always to all of the supporters on there
these videos would not be possible
without those people so thank you so
much and next time as as usual I have no
idea what's gonna be next in this series
but I should probably look at my list
and if you have any suggestions for what
you would like to see next
in this A+ Ball series please leave a
comment below and I will see you next
time
goodbye
[Music]